







Head-Enterprise Integration seeking roles in IT Project Management, Software Development, Software Design, Enterprise Architecture, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Enterprise Applications, IT Security Management, MS SQL Server, ASP. Net, Java, C#

Total Experience: 16 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: Masters [Information Technology]

Current Designation: Head-Enterprise Integration

Current Company: Process International SA

Current Location: ghana, west africa

Pref. Location: South Africa, United Arab Emirates

(UAE).United States (US)

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming

Maintenance

Role: Head/VP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Head-Enterprise Integration, Head/NP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO,,IT Project Management, Software Development, Software Design, Enterprise Architecture, Application Development, Requirement Gathering, Enterprise

Applications, IT Security Management, MS SQL Server

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

### Summary

Over 14 years' experience in software development, process automation, SOA middleware integration, mobile and web portal development and enterprise platform implementation in technology firms and multi-language banking institution. Highly proficient in Java, C#.Net & PHP Programming languages.

Involved in delivery of over 25 small, medium and large-scale development, integration & platform deployment initiatives/projects in many countries in Africa.

Strong experience, practical knowledge and high proficiency in Flexcube Core Banking Integration & Implementation and interface support using FLEXML, ISO interface & DE upload.

Strong experience in integration and custom interface development around - Postilion, Tieto CMS, Oracle Siebel CRM, SWIFT, Active Directory, Internet Banking, BankCollect,OMNI and many other enterprise applications

Strong experience & functional knowledge of enterprise application integration, enterprise service bus (ESB), service orchestration

# **Work Experience**

Process International SA as Head-Enterprise Integration Jun 2018 to Till Date

## Responsibilities

Design & implement enterprise integration strategy & framework for the organization in consultation with stakeholders and consultants.

Lead & manage the design, execution & delivery of middleware integration between third party systems & Flexcube 12 core banking implementation for the Ecobank Group

Translate business requirements to detailed technical specification & design documents for developers & external consultants using UML standards - Visio, Use Case, Flowchart, Activity Diagram etc.

Design & Implement framework for Open Banking API for the bank

Provide technical support for new enterprise application deployment and implementation

Provide integration support for Flexcube, MULE, Postilion, CMS, Oracle CRM, Internet Banking Platform,

Omniflow, external third party or partner payment or billing system.

Participate in maintenance & review of documentations on Bank Enterprise Application Architecture,

API, Service Registry & Repository

Regularly conduct internal team mentoring, knowledge sharing and training on best practices

associated with design, integrations & documentation

Prompt fix and resolution of application issues, bugs, errors in production or live system

Manage technical relationships with external consultants for prompt resolutions of issues, deployment

of fixes and upgrades, development of new modules

Develop proactive application maintenance procedures

Ensure application strict compliance to IS Policy, IT Security & Regulatory Guidelines

eProcess International SA as Senior Manager, Head, Mobile, Digital & Payments, Group Technology, **Ecobank Group** Jun 2012 to Jun 2018

#### Responsibilities

# **Important**

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

เของบบเอเมแแน

Design, document, and develop middleware integration services or interfaces, service orchestration, message routing, data transformation and service deployment using MULE ESB & other Java Application Servers using API-led & SOA-based approach.

Coordinate & participate in design & development of web application, portal development, application customization & enhancements of existing platform functionalities due to change or new business

Translate business requirements to detailed technical specification & design documents for developers & external consultants using UML standards - Visio, Use Case, Flowchart, Activity Diagram etc.

Provide technical support for new enterprise application deployment and implementation

Provide integration support for Flexcube, MULE, Postilion, CMS, Oracle CRM, Internet Banking Platform, Omniflow, external third party or partner payment or billing system.

Participate in maintenance & review of documentations on Bank Enterprise Application Architecture,

API, Service Registry & Repository

Regularly conduct internal team mentoring, knowledge sharing and training on best practices associated with design, integrations & documentation

Prompt fix and resolution of application issues, bugs, errors in production or live system

Manage technical relationships with external consultants for prompt resolutions of issues, deployment

of fixes and upgrades, development of new modules

Develop proactive application maintenance procedures

Monitor and coordinate source code versioning in Visual SourceSafe & TortoiseSVN Ensure application strict compliance to IS Policy, IT Security & Regulatory Guidelines eProcess International SA, Accra, Ghana Jun. 2012 - Apr. 2017

Position: Manager

Team Lead - Integration, Interface Support & Software Development

#### Responsibilities

Design, document, and develop middleware integration services or interfaces, service orchestration, message routing, data transformation and service deployment using MULE ESB & other Java Application Servers using API-led & SOA-based approach.

Coordinate & participate in design & development of web application, portal development, application customization & enhancements of existing platform functionalities due to change or new business requirements

Translate business requirements to detailed technical specification & design documents for developers & external consultants using UML standards - Visio, Use Case, Flowchart, Activity Diagram etc.

Provide technical support for new enterprise application deployment and implementation

Provide integration support for Flexcube, MULE, Postilion, CMS, Oracle CRM, Internet Banking Platform, Omniflow, external third party or partner payment or billing system.

Participate in maintenance & review of documentations on Bank Enterprise Application Architecture, API, Service Registry & Repository

Regularly conduct internal team mentoring, knowledge sharing and training on best practices associated with design, integrations & documentation

Prompt fix and resolution of application issues, bugs, errors in production or live system

Manage technical relationships with external consultants for prompt resolutions of issues, deployment of fixes and upgrades, development of new modules

Develop proactive application maintenance procedures

Monitor and coordinate source code versioning in Visual SourceSafe & TortoiseSVN

Ensure application strict compliance to IS Policy, IT Security & Regulatory Guidelines

#### Ecobank Nigeria Limited as Developer - Integration, Interface Support & Software Development Oct 2008 to Jun 2012

# Responsibilities

Design & development of custom software to meet specific business requirements from users Translate business requirements to detailed technical specification & design documents for developers & external consultants using UML standard & tools - Visio, Use Case, Flowchart, Activity Diagram etc Develop interfaces & integration services for enterprise applications - Flexcube, Postilion, and SMFT. Coding program modules and integration of components that meet design specifications Report Design & Generation using JasperReport, Crystal Report & Business Object Support testing and quality assurance process of application developed Deployment of application developed on Web/Application Server environment -Tomcat, Jboss,

Document Functional Requirements, class/object modeling diagram, entity relationship diagram, unit

testing code, unit program codes

^ Back to Top

### **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from University of Ilorin, Ilorin, Nigeria in 2004

PG: Masters (Information Technology) from University of Lagos, Nigeria in 2014

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: IJMB A Level Certificate Oracle Certified Associate (OCA) in Oracle 10g Sun Certified Java Programmer for the Java 2 Platform 1.4 (SCJP) Information Technology Infrastructure Library (ITIL) Associate MULE Developer Certification PRINCE2 Foundation & Practitioner Certification

^ Back to Top

# IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
MS Office Suite	
MS EXCEL, WORD	
Powerpoint, Access	
Vieual Pagia	

VISUAI DASIU			
JAVA			

^ Back to Top

### **Affirmative Action**

Physically Challenged: No

### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.